She disappeared?
Zniknęła?
Hey, why is this happening?
Dlaczego nas to spotyka?
EPISODE 2
ODCINEK 2
Why is this happening?
Dlaczego to się dzieje?
What is going on?
Co się dzieje?
She's gone.
Zniknęła.
Mao's gone.
Mao zniknęła.
Shiho?
Shiho?
Where did she go? I'm scared.
Gdzie ona jest? Boję się.
What?
Co?
-There was something outside the door! -No!
- Coś przeszło za drzwiami! - Nie!
Mao's phone! She was looking at it before she disappeared.
Telefon Mao! Patrzyła na niego, zanim zniknęła.
Give it here, Kageyama! Hurry!
Daj go, Kageyama! Szybko!
What is it?
O co chodzi?
Quit acting like you know what's going on!
Przestań udawać, że wiesz, o co chodzi!
Mirei!
Mirei!
Are you listening?
Słuchasz mnie?
What a bitch!
Suka!
Let's get out of here before we get all killed!
Uciekajmy stąd, zanim wszystkie zginiemy!
Stop being so passive!
Zacznijmy działać!
Let's get out of here!
Uciekajmy stąd!
Why do we have to be here?
Czemu tu jesteśmy?
I can't understand this!
Nic z tego nie rozumiem!
How can we escape?
Jak mamy uciec?
I don't know, but we have to try!
Nie wiem, ale musimy spróbować!
We have to try something!
Musimy coś wymyślić.
Think! Come on, everyone! Think!
Pomyślcie, dziewczyny!
There must be something!
Musi być jakiś sposób.
Wait!
Czekajcie!
Let's all calm down.
Musimy się uspokoić.
In times like this, we...
W takich momentach...
Shut your fucking mouth, smarty-pants!
Zamknij mordę, mądralo!
Don't talk like that.
Nie mów tak.
Do you have a problem with it?
Przeszkadza ci to?
Start looking for a way out!
To zacznij szukać wyjścia!
I wonder if we really can escape.
Ciekawe, czy jesteśmy w stanie uciec.
What's this?
Co to jest?
What is it? It's scary.
Co to? Boję się.
Look! There's something inside.
Patrz, w środku coś jest.
A key? It's a key!
Klucz? To klucz!
A key for what?
Do czego?
How should I know?
Skąd mam wiedzieć?
But it's a key!
Ale to klucz!
What is this thing?
Co to jest?
It won't open.
Nie da się otworzyć.
Fuck this thing!
Pieprzyć to!
I wonder if it's a key for these.
Ciekawe, czy to klucz do nich.
How should I know? It probably is.
Skąd mam wiedzieć? Pewnie tak.
How will we get it out?
Jak się dowiemy?
Wait!
Czekaj!
Why?
Dlaczego?
Won't they get angry if you break it?
Nie będą źli, jeśli to rozbijesz?
The way things are, I couldn't care less.
W tej sytuacji niewiele mnie to obchodzi.
-Hold on. -I think we have...
- Czekaj. - Chyba...
Shut your mouths!
Zamknijcie się!
-Look at that! -All right!
- Patrzcie! - Dobra nasza!
This will set us free. I'm sure of it.
Dzięki temu się uwolnimy. Jestem pewna.
What?
Co?
Hey! What the fuck is with this?
Hej! Co jest, do cholery?
What are we going to do, Sarina?
Co my teraz zrobimy, Sarina?
Sarina!
Sarina!
When Mirei is like this, she can't hear anything.
Kiedy Mirei tak wygląda, nie słyszy was.
Yeah, she's always like that when she's focused on something.
Tak, gdy jest bardzo skupiona.
Mei, let go for a second.
Mei, puść mnie.
Sarina.
Sarina.
Shiho, listen. Let's call for help.
Słuchaj, Shiho. Wołajmy o pomoc.
How are we going to do that?
Jak to zrobimy?
-The skylight. -What?
- Świetlik. - Co?
That skylight leads outside.
Prowadzi na zewnątrz.
Let's break it and get the attention of people outside.
Zbijmy go i zwróćmy na siebie uwagę ludzi z zewnątrz.
Break the skylight?
Zbić świetlik?
-We can't do that! -Why?
- Nie możemy! - Dlaczego?
Don't aggravate whoever did this! Someone else could disappear!
Nie drażnijmy tych, którzy to zrobili. Kolejna osoba zniknie!
-I think Mei is right. -Find something to throw.
- Mei ma rację. - Trzeba tylko czymś rzucić.
Don't do it, Sarina.
Nie, Sarina.
This key...
Klucz...
It doesn't fit.
nie pasuje.
Damn it.
Cholera.
What a stupid key!
Co za głupi klucz!
I've had it!
Mam dość.
-Actually... -What do you want?
- Właściwie... - Co?
Look.
Patrzcie.
These were on the table.
Były na stole.
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
Czemu nic mi wcześniej nie powiedziałaś?
-I tried. -But then you got angry.
- Próbowałam. - Ale zaczęłaś krzyczeć.
So what? Tell me you found them! Now I'm all wet!
No i? Mogłaś powiedzieć! Teraz jestem cała mokra!
Don't get angry, Kyoko.
Nie denerwuj się, Kyoko.
I'm not angry.
Nie denerwuję się.
I'll try every one of these.
Sprawdzę wszystkie.
What the hell is going on?
Co tam się dzieje?
Don't! That's dangerous!
Nie! To niebezpieczne!
One more time!
Jeszcze raz!
I guess it's no good.
Chyba się nie uda.
That's dangerous!
To niebezpieczne!
-Do it again! Find something hard! -That's dangerous...
- Jeszcze raz! Znajdź coś twardego! - To niebezpieczne...
It's too dangerous! Don't do it!
To zbyt niebezpieczne! Przestań!
There's a clue somewhere. There must be.
Gdzieś musi być jakaś wskazówka.
What?
Co?
-That! -What?
- To! - Co?
Not this one.
Nie ten.
Not this one either.
Ani ten.
Damn it.
Cholera.
But it's the right size.
Przecież mają odpowiedni rozmiar.
Which one is it?
Który to?
This is really ticking me off!
Jak mnie to wkurza!
I wish I'd practiced more.
Szkoda, że nie ćwiczyłam więcej.
Shiho?
Shiho?
Hey! Don't throw it without warning us!
Hej! Nie rzucaj bez ostrzeżenia!
It's no good. It won't break.
To nic nie da, nie rozbije się.
What should we do, Mirei?
Co teraz, Mirei?
Whatever you look at, it reminds you of something.
Wszystko, co widzimy, z czymś nam się kojarzy.
What does that mean?
Co to znaczy?
I think Mirei figured something out.
Mirei chyba na coś wpadła.
Damn it! It's no good!
Cholera! Nie pasuje!
They wouldn't put the keys to this within reach anyway.
Nie położyliby pasujących kluczy tak blisko.
-What? Am I wrong? -Kyoko!
- Co? Nie mam racji? - Kyoko!
-Don't get angry. -I'm not.
- Nie złość się. - Nie złoszczę się.
Are we all going to disappear?
Wszystkie znikniemy?
Get up here, everyone! Hurry!
Chodźcie tu wszystkie, szybko!
I think Mirei figured something out.
Mirei chyba na coś wpadła.
"I Guess Everything Reminds You of Something."
„I guess everything reminds you of something”.
Is she okay?
Dobrze się czuje?
Kyoko.
Kyoko.
What does it mean?
Co to znaczy?
Whatever you look at, it reminds you of something.
Wszystko, co widzimy, z czymś nam się kojarzy.
It's the title of that book.
To tytuł książki.
It's by Hemingway.
To Hemingway.
A book?
Książka?
Hummingway?
Hummingway?
-Who is that? -Kyoko.
- Kto to? - Kyoko.
There must be some reason why only these members of our class
Z jakiegoś powodu jest tutaj tylko część dziewczyn
have been gathered here.
z naszej klasy.
There must be some meaning to this crazy room too.
Ten dziwny pokój też musi mieć jakieś znaczenie.
When I realized that, I found that book.
Kiedy to sobie uświadomiłam, znalazłam tę książkę.
I think the title is a message to us.
To chyba wiadomość dla nas.
Sorry. What is the title again?
Jak brzmiał ten tytuł?
Are you joking?
Nie żartuj sobie.
How can I understand that? Say it in Japanese.
Nic nie rozumiem! Mów po japońsku!
Whatever you look at, it reminds you of something.
Wszystko, co widzimy, z czymś nam się kojarzy.
I can't even understand the Japanese. Did you get it?
Dalej nie rozumiem. Wiesz, o co chodzi?
-What is that book about, Mirei? -Say something that makes sense.
- O czym jest ta książka? - Powiedz coś, co ma sens.
I read it a long time ago.
Czytałam ją dawno temu.
It's about a man and his son.
Jest o mężczyźnie i jego synu.
The father teaches his son about shooting and writing.
Ojciec uczy syna strzelać i pisać.
Ultimately, he realizes that his son is a failure.
W końcu dochodzi do wniosku, że jego syn to nieudacznik.
Why is that interesting?
Co w tym ciekawego?
It's interesting because you can sense the love between father and son.
Czuć w niej miłość pomiędzy ojcem a synem.
That's what I think.
Tak myślę.
But it didn't get published while Hemingway was alive.
Ale opublikowano ją dopiero po śmierci autora.
So, I think there was something about it that kept him from publishing it.
Więc chyba coś go powstrzymywało przed jej wydaniem.
Who cares what you think?
Kogo obchodzi twoje zdanie?
What has that got to do with this?
Co to ma wspólnego z nami?
The title is one of the things that the son says.
Tytuł to zdanie wypowiadane przez syna.
Whatever you look at, it reminds you of something.
Wszystko, co widzimy, z czymś nam się kojarzy.
I think whoever brought us here
Myślę, że ten, kto nas tu ściągnął,
is telling us to remember something.
chce, żebyśmy coś sobie przypomniały.
Remember what?
Ale co?
That's crazy. You've been reading too many mystery books.
To jakieś wariactwo. Czytasz za dużo kryminałów.
Kyoko, keep quiet and listen to what Mirei has to say.
Cicho, Kyoko. Posłuchajmy tego, co ma do powiedzenia Mirei.
There is this one empty seat.
Jedno miejsce jest wolne.
This is the phone Mao left.
To telefon Mao.
It's Miho's seat.
To miejsce Miho.
This is where Miho sat.
Ona tam siedziała.
You mean, they want us to remember Miho?
Czyli mamy sobie przypomnieć Miho?
Right. I think they want us to remember Miho.
Myślę, że o to im chodzi.
But...
Ale...
You know, Mao disappeared after remembering that.
Mao zniknęła zaraz po tym, jak sobie to przypomniała.
Mirei.
Mirei.
Okay.
Dobrze.
Let's reminisce about her.
Powspominajmy Miho.
Miho Watanabe.
Miho Watanabe.
Eighteen years old.
Osiemnastolatka.
She was the daughter of Shichiro Watanabe,
Córka Shichiro Watanabe,
prefectural assemblyman and chairman of the biggest hospital in the prefecture.
radnego prefektury i dyrektora jej największego szpitala.
The charisma she inherited made her the center of attention at school.
Odziedziczona po ojcu charyzma stawiała ją w centrum uwagi w szkole.
Then, well...
Potem...
In June?
W czerwcu?
In June, she had an accident at school that confined her to a wheelchair.
Miho miała w szkole wypadek, przez który została przykuta do wózka.
Then she stopped coming to school
Potem przestała chodzić na lekcje...
and went missing at the end of last year.
i zaginęła pod koniec zeszłego roku.
Nothing changed.
Nic się nie zmieniło.
Didn't she just drop out of school?
Czy ona nie odeszła po prostu ze szkoły?
No. She moved overseas, right?
Przeprowadziła się za granicę, prawda?
I heard she and her dad moved out of town one night.
Słyszałam, że wyjechała z ojcem z miasta.
Everyone heard something different.
Każdy zna inną wersję.
Miho is...
Miho to...
POWER OFF: CHARGE BATTERY
BATERIA ROZŁADOWANA
We need to find out
Musimy się dowiedzieć,
where Miho really is and why she isn't here.
gdzie naprawdę jest Miho i dlaczego nie tutaj.
What do you mean by that, Mirei?
Co masz na myśli, Mirei?
Hey! Quit talking like a know-it-all!
Hej! Nie udawaj, że wszystko wiesz!
The people here are
Są tu osoby...
the ones who bullied Miho.
które znęcały się nad Miho.
I'm not sure, but...
Nie jestem pewna, ale...
this might be a punishment for bullying Miho.
myślę, że to kara za dręczenie Miho.
I didn't bully her directly.
Nie znęcałam się nad nią.
But...
Ale...
tolerating it is just as bad.
nie reagowałam.
It's reason enough to be punished.
To wystarczający powód.
You're telling us that this is a punishment by Miho?
Uważasz, że to kara za nękanie Miho?
Why would Miho do that?
Czemu Miho miałaby to zrobić?
So, Miho made Mao disappear?
Mao zniknęła przez Miho?
Come to think of it, Mao bullied her the most.
Prawdę mówiąc, Mao najbardziej się nad nią znęcała.
They used to be good friends.
Kiedyś się przyjaźniły.
Let's all apologize
Powinnyśmy wszystkie
to Miho.
przeprosić Miho.
Let's all remember Miho.
Powspominajmy ją.
"Whatever you look at, it reminds you of something."
„Wszystko, co widzimy, z czymś nam się kojarzy”.
-Mei? -You're so stupid.
- Mei? - Jesteś głupia.
What?
Co?
-A punishment from Miho? That's stupid. -Don't talk like that!
- Kara od Miho? To durne. - Nie mów tak!
You will disappear! Stop it!
Przestań, bo znikniesz!
I'm not afraid of Miho!
Nie boję się Miho!
Did Miho prepare all of these?
Sama to przygotowała?
She must be filthy rich.
Musi być obrzydliwie bogata.
Cut that out.
Przestań.
If Miho is doing this, I'm not scared at all.
Jeśli to sprawka Miho, wcale się nie boję.
These leg-irons are stupid!
Te kajdany są durne!
Hey! Hurry up and take these off! I want to leave right now!
Szybko, pozbądźmy się ich! Chcę stąd iść!
Don't drink it! I have a bad feeling about it!
Nie pij tego! Mam złe przeczucie!
What are you afraid of?
Czego się boisz?
Are you sure that's okay?
Jesteś tego pewna?
There was a key in the water.
W wodzie był klucz.
If this is revenge, there could be poison in it.
Jeśli to zemsta, może być zatruta.
I could drink this forever.
Będę piła, ile chcę.
I need to use the toilet! Let me go right now!
Muszę do łazienki! Wypuść mnie!
Are you listening?
Słyszysz mnie?
Kyoko! Don't drink it!
Kyoko! Nie pij tego!
I think it's okay.
Jest w porządku.
This is great!
Pyszne!
Really?
Naprawdę?
This room is...
Ten pokój...
Help me!
Pomocy!
You're kidding! Why are you sick?
Żartujecie sobie! Co wam jest?
Kyoko drank it, so I did too!
Kyoko wypiła, więc ja też!
It's not my fault!
To nie moja wina!
Just kidding!
Żartuję!
You guys got so freaked out.
Ale się przestraszyłyście.
"Remember"? Screw you!
„Powspominajmy ją”? Walcie się!
This kidnapping is the real problem! It's fucked up!
Problemem jest to porwanie! To pojebane!
-Cut it out! -You cut it out!
- Przestań! - Sama przestań!
Again?
Znowu?
What's with this clock?
O co chodzi z tym zegarem?
-What's that? -What is that sound?
- Co to? - Co to za dźwięk?
You must be kidding.
To jakiś żart.
After this bell rang,
Po tym dzwonku...
the room went dark
zrobiło się ciemno,
and Mao...
a Mao...
Mao disappeared.
Mao zniknęła.
So,
Więc...
another one of us will vanish?
teraz zniknie kolejna?
Will we be killed?
Zabiją nas?
Sarina.
Sarina.
Save me, Sarina.
Ratunku, Sarina.
Mei, what should we do?
Co mamy zrobić, Mei?
Mei.
Mei.
Apologize.
Przeproś.
Apologize to Miho.
Przeproś Miho.
Hurry up and apologize, Sarina.
Szybko, przeproś, Sarina.
What?
Co?
It's your fault.
To twoja wina.
It's all your fault.
To wszystko przez ciebie.
Mei?
Mei?
What are you talking about?
O czym ty mówisz?
What do you mean?
Co masz na myśli?
It's not my fault.
To nie moja wina.
It was Sarina who did it.
Sarina to zrobiła.
What?
Co?
THIS DRAMA IS A WORK OF FICTION.
PRZEDSTAWIONY SERIAL JEST FIKCJĄ.
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey
Napisy: Arianna Sugier